Guide to the Robert W. Taylor Papers M2281
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert W. Taylor papers
1932-2017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Taylor, R. W. (Robert William), 1932-2017
Taylor, Kurt H.
M2281
20 Linear Feet 38 boxes
2.5 terabyte(s) CLOSED until processed
Papers and materials related to the work and life of Robert W. Taylor. Topics covered include ARPA and the birth of Arpanet; Xerox PARC, particularly the Computer Science Laboratory and the Systems Science Laboratory; and Digital Equipment Corporation's Systems Research Laboratory.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy. Born-digital material in Series 14's hard drive is CLOSED until processed.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was given by Kurt H. Taylor to Stanford University, Special Collections in October, 2017.
Biographical / Historical
Robert William Taylor (February 10th, 1932 – April 13th, 2017) was a project manager, executive director, and laboratory chief known for overseeing a number of advances in personal computing and internet technology throughout the tenure of his career. Though not a trained computer scientist, Robert Taylor worked with many influential teams, engineers, and scientists in the world of computer technology, including J.C.R. Licklider, Charles Thacker, Butler Lampson, Alan Kay, Paul Baran, Douglas Engelbart, Robert Metcalfe, Ivan Sutherland, and Leslie Lamport.
Taylor’s directorial and managerial work at the Department of Defense’s Advanced Research Projects Agency (ARPA), Xerox’s Palo Alto Research Center (PARC), and Digital Equipment Corporation’s Systems Research Center (SRC) from the 1960s through the 1990s put him at the center of the early days of the internet and personal computing; he was directly involved with such influential technology and systems as ARPAnet (the predecessor to the modern internet), Ethernet, the computer mouse, graphical user interfaces, the Xerox Alto (considered the world’s first personal computer), WYSIWYG word processing, and laser printers.
Born in Dallas, Texas in 1932, Taylor graduated from Mercedes High School in Mercedes, Texas in 1948 at the age of 16. He attended Southern Methodist University before joining the US Naval Reserve. After his active service ended, Taylor returned to college and eventually earned Bachelor’s and Master’s degrees in psychology from the University of Texas at Austin. Taylor went on to take a number of engineering and research positions with companies such as Martin Marietta and ACF Industries before taking a position as project manager at NASA’s Office of Advanced Research and Technology in Washington, D.C.. In 1962, while working at NASA as a project manager, Taylor directed funding towards Douglas Engelbart’s “oN-Line System” (NLS) project at Stanford Research Institute (later SRI International), which led to innovations such as the computer mouse and hypertext.
In 1966, Robert Taylor joined the Department of Defense’s Advanced Research Projects Agency (ARPA), then the nation’s largest computer systems research effort. At ARPA, Taylor worked under J.C.R. Licklider at the Information Processing Techniques Office. Licklider, known for his influential 1960 article “Man-Computer Symbiosis”, shared a background in psychology and psychoacoustics with Taylor, and the pair authored the article “The Computer as a Communication Device” in 1968. During his tenure at ARPA, Taylor conceived of and oversaw ARPAnet, an attempt to connect different research networks under Taylor’s purview that became the technical foundation for the internet.
In 1970, Taylor moved to the Silicon Valley to join Xerox’s new Palo Alto Research Center, which became known as Xerox PARC. As laboratory chief of Xerox PARC’s Computer Science Laboratory (CSL), Taylor brought in a number of engineers and designers whom he knew from his research funding work at ARPA, including Butler Lampson, Charles Thacker, and Alan Kay. Taylor’s team developed the Alto, considered the first personal computer as well as the basic model for later personal computing innovations such as Apple’s Lisa computer and Microsoft’s Windows system.
After a series of disagreements with Xerox’s executive management, Taylor resigned from his position at the company in 1983. His departure preceded a number of resignations from Xerox PARC, including engineers who came to join Taylor at his new position at Digital Equipment Corporation’s Systems Research Center (SRC) in Palo Alto. Other members of Taylor’s CSL team went on to do innovative work at companies such as Microsoft, Adobe Systems, 3Com, Sun Microsystems, and Apple. Taylor remained at Digital SRC until his retirement in 1996. Amongst the projects he oversaw at Digital SRC was AltaVista, an early internet search engine that achieved considerable popularity in the late 1990s.
Robert W. Taylor was awarded the National Medal of Technology and Innovation in 1999 and the National Academy of Engineering’s Draper Prize in 2004, both in recognition of his contributions to the development of the internet and modern computing. In 2010, the University of Texas at Austin established the Robert W. Taylor Endowed Presidential Fellowship in Taylor’s honor. He was additionally named an Association for Computer Machinery (ACM) Fellow in 1994 and a Fellow of the Computer History Museum in 2013.
Scope and Contents
The Robert W. Taylor papers contain memoranda, correspondence, technical documentation and specifications, photographs, slides, negatives, newspaper and magazine clippings, printed emails, notes, and a variety of media on tape and disc. The materials included range from 1932, the year of Taylor’s birth, until 2017, the year of his death, with the bulk of the materials related to his work at the Department of Defense from 1966 – 1969, at Xerox PARC from 1970 – 1983, and at Digital SRC from 1983 – 1996.
The papers contain significant documentation related to Digital SRC’s equipment, facilities, staff, and marketing materials, with the 1990s at Digital SRC extensively represented through photographs, slides, and negatives. There are numerous publications written by Robert W. Taylor as well as articles about him or referring to him in newspapers, magazines, alumni documents, and award announcements. Items related to Taylor’s National Medal of Technology and the associated ceremony, as well as other recognition he received later in life, are also included, as are various documents related to Taylor’s employment at Howey Academy, the University of Utah, NASA, ACF Industries, and Martin Marietta, as well as his military service.
ARPANET (Computer network); Silicon Valley; Computer science.; Internet--History; Computer industry--United States--History; Taylor, R. W. (Robert William), 1932-2017; Taylor, Kurt H.; Xerox Corporation. Palo Alto Research Center; Digital Equipment Corporation. Systems Research Center; Xerox PARC (Firm); Licklider, J. C. R.
- Series 1. Biographical and Personal Files
  - Robert W. Taylor Memorial Pamphlet (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - LaeRoc Income Fund Materials (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - "CBI-OH 154 Robert Taylor Duplicate, 1 of 3" Cassette Tape (Box 30, Object 9)
  - "CBI-OH 154 Robert Taylor Duplicate, 2 of 3" Cassette Tape (Box 30, Object 10)
  - "CBI-OH 154 Robert Taylor Duplicate, 3 of 3" Cassette Tape (Box 30, Object 11)
  - Photos and Contact Sheets of Robert W. Taylor (Box 25, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Touch Football Game Photos (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Stenograph Notebook (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - "Resumes" (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Personal Note Pad (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Letter from Paul Baran, 2004 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - "Letters" (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Nan Geschke (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Publications (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Misc. Quotes (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - "Wells Fargo Nikko Investment Advisors 1992 Client Colloquium" Videocassette (Box 31, Object 2 - 3)
  - Licklider Obituary, Letters from Louise Licklider, etc. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Passports (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Calendars and Names (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Memo, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Statement of Personal History (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Address File in Metal Box (Box 20, Object 1)
  - Daily Planners (Unfoldered), 1964 - 1996 (Box 21)
    Scope and Contents
    Not every year represented.
  - Business Card Index (Box 20, Object 2)
  - Pilot Flight Record, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - University Notes (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - GRE Data, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Marriage License, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Wedding Photo (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - SMU Transcript, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Diploma from Mercedes High School (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Two Instantaneous Discs Recorded in San Antonio, Texas, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 1 - 2)
    One disc is labeled "Bobby Taylor - Jimminy Cricket -- Rounded Up in Glory, June 26th, 1945".
  - Intelligence Test, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Baby Photos (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Standard Certificate of Birth (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series 2. Department of Defense/ARPA
  - "Bob's Photo of Arpanet Group" (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - "An Historical Study of the Beginnings of Packet Switching" (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - "The ARPA/MRDC Computer Lab", 1971 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - ARPA Records (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 'A History of the ARPANET', 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Notes on ARPANET (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Post-Government Employment Activities (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Reports (ARPA-related) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - ARPA PI Conference, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - ARPA Documents (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Photo - ARPA (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Expressions of Appreciation - ARPA (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "ELIZA" (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - DOD Computer Institute, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Erma, etc. - ARPA (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Intergalactic Computer Network" Memo (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - DOD Passports and Documents (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Certificate for Education and Training (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - VA Info (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Official Department of Defense Record (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series 3. Xerox PARC
  - "Xerox PARC - 22 minutes of Bob Taylor 1976 - 1980" Betacam Tape (Box 31, Object 4)
  - "PARC 1983 + 1984, Random" Slides (Box 26, Folder 4 - 11)
  - "1983 PARC Helicopter" Slides (Box 26, Folder 1 - 3)
  - Misc. Xerox PARC Photos (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Alto - Japan (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Letters from Squires re: Xerox Resignation (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - PUP and TCP Chronology - J.F. Schoch (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - "If Youth Knew, If Age Could" (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Thacker - "The Xerox Alto Architecture", 2013 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - CSL Staff Research Interests (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - "What Might CSL Do in the Next Ten Years?" (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Xerox PARC Activities Report, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - PARC Personnel Files (Box 9, Folder 1 - 2)
  - "Software/Systems Seminar", 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Graphic System Notebook" File, 1973 - 1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Display Study Memos and Reports", 1972 - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 'BCC' File: "Preliminary Proposal for a Systems Group Within Xerox PARC' (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Dealer Minutes, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Chronological list of included memos:
    1/19/72 (memo of 2/11/72)
    1/26/72 (memo of 2/9/72)
    2/2/72 (memo of 2/9/72)
    2/9/72 (memo of 2/14/72; "before editing" summary, no date)
    2/16/72 (memo of 2/22/72; 2/17/72 draft)
    2/21/72 (memo of 3/21/72)
    2/23/72 (memo of 5/10/72)
    2/29/72 (memo of 3/2/72)
    3/7/72 (memo of 4/21/72)
    3/14/72 (memo of 5/15/72)
    3/21/72 (memo of the same date)
    3/28/73 (memo of 3/29/72)
    4/4/72 (memo of 4/5/72)
    4/11/72 (memo of 4/14/72)
    4/18/72 (memo of the same date)
    4/25/72 (memo of 4/28/72)
    5/2/72 (memo of 5/8/72)
    5/7/72 (memo of 5/15/72)
    5/9/72 (memo of 5/11/72)
    7/25/72 (memo of the same date)
    8/15/72 (memo of the same date)
    9/5/72 (memo of 9/22/72)
    9/12/72 (memo of 9/28/72; draft)
    9/19/72 (memo of 9/21/72)
    10/3/72 (memo of the same date)
    10/10/72 (announcement of 10/6/72; memo of 11/6/72; unpublished version of Dealer Minutes for 10/10/72; a draft of Minutes)
  - Dealer Minutes, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    5/8/73 (memo of the same date)
    5/15/73 (memo of the same date)
    5/29/73 (memo of the same date)
    6/5/73 (memo of the same date)
    6/19/73 (memo of 6/20/73)
    6/26/73 (memo of 6/28/73)
    7/3/73 (memo of 7/5/73)
    7/10/73 (memo of the same date)
    7/17/73 (memo of the same date)
    7/24/73 (memo of the same date)
    7/31/73 (memo of the same date; revised 8/02/73)
    8/7/73 (memo of the same date)
    8/14/73 (memo of 8/15/73)
    8/21/73 (memo of the same date)
    8/28/73 (memo of 8/29/73)
    9/4/73 (memo of the same date)
    9/11/73 (memo of 9/13/73)
    9/?/73 (memo of 9/25/73)
    10/02/73 (memo of the same date)
    10/19/73 (memo of the same date)
    10/?/73 (memo of 10/16/73)
    10/23/73 (memo of the same date)
    10/30/73 (memo of the same date)
    11/6/73 (memo of 11/7/73)
    11/13/73 (memo of 11/16/73)
    12/04/73 (no date)
  - Dealer Minutes, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    1/?/74 (memo of 1/9/74)
    1/15/74 (announcement of 1/11/74)
    2/5/74 (announcement of 2/4/74)
    2/12/74 (announcement of 2/11/74; memo of 2/13/74)
    2/19/74 (memo of 2/25/74)
    2/26/74 (memo of 2/26/74)
    3/5/74 (memo of 3/7/74)
    3/12/74 (announcement of 3/7/74; memo of 3/13/74)
    3/19/74 (announcement of 3/18/74; memo of 3/22/74)
    3/?/74 (announcement of 3/19/74)
    3/26/74 (memo of 3/30/74)
    4/1/74 (memo of 4/2/74)
    4/9/74 (announcement of 4/4/74)
    4/?/74 (memo of 4/11/74)
    4/16/74 (memo of 4/17/74)
    4/23/74 (memo of the same date)
    4/30/74 (memo of the same date)
    5/7/74 (memo of the same date)
    5/14/74 (memo of the same date)
    5/21/74 (memo of the same date)
    5/28/74 (memo of the same date)
    6/4/74 (memo of the same date)
    6/11/74 (announcement of 6/10/74; memo of 6/11/74)
    6/18/74 (announcement of 6/17/74; memo of 6/24/74; memo about the visitor control is attached; handwritten draft of the content of the Dealer Minutes of 6/18/74 from J. Elkind; first version of the memo of 6/21/74)
    6/25/74 (memo of 6/27/74)
    7/2/74 (announcement of 6/27/74; memo of 7/2/74)
    7/9/74 (memo of 7/10/74)
    7/16/74 (memo of the same date)
    7/23/74 (memo of 7/24/74)
    7/30/74 (memo of the same date)
    8/6/74 (handwritten; no date)
    8/13/74 (announcement of 7/19/74; announcement of 8/11)
    8/20/74 (memo of the same date)
    11/19/74 (announcement of 11/15/74)
    12/10/74 (announcement of 12/4/74)
  - "IEEE Spectrum", 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Pake's PARC Story, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Leaving Xerox - Misc. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Resignations from Xerox (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Letters re: Resignation (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Kearns and Misc. CSL Notes (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - CSL Publications List - 1973 - 1983 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "Fortune", 1983-09-05 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "A PARC Agenda?", 1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Butler W. Lampson on Systems Design (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Seybold Reports, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - General Memos - CSL (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Structure of Computer Science, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Tech Transfer - PARC (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Reports - 1980s (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Ethernet and Alto, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - CSL Future Notes (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Ethernet Memo, CSL Hardware Activity Memo, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Alto (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Larry Tesler - 1971 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Expressions of Appreciation - PARC (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - PARC Photos (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - PARC Chapter (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Xerox - Resume, etc. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - PAs (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Series 4. Digital SRC
  - "SRC Archival Pix" CD Binder (Box 34, Object 1)
    Approximately 60 discs with Digital SRC-related photos and other media. Appears to include duplicates from other Digital SRC photo files.
  - "Bob Taylor (Dub)" Videocassette (Box 32, Object 8)
  - "SRC Construction and 5 Year Interview with Butler Lampson, 1984" (Box 32, Object 3)
  - "Corp Research DECWORLD Media Briefing" Videocassette, 1990-07-16 (Box 31, Object 1)
  - "SRC Skating 19 Nov 86" DV Tape (Box 30, Object 7)
  - "3 FRED 5668" Slides (Box 30, Folder 5 - 6)
  - "3 FRED 5665" Slides (Box 30, Folder 3 - 4)
  - "3 FRED" Slides (Box 30, Folder 1 - 2)
  - "NY Times" Slides (Box 29, Folder 19 - 20)
  - "Clear Desk CL" Slides (Box 29, Folder 17 - 18)
  - Unidentified Equipment Slides (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - "Auto Net 1972" Slides (Box 29, Folder 14 - 15)
  - "P Max" Slides (Box 29, Folder 12 - 13)
  - "NY Times" Slides (Box 29, Folder 10 - 11)
  - "Paste Dot" Slides (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - "SRC Exterior Outtakes 9097" Slides (Box 29, Folder 7 - 8)
  - "PEX 8221" Slides (Box 29, Folder 5 - 6)
  - "FF Parts 5989" Slides (Box 29, Folder 3 - 4)
  - "Fire Fly Show Set 8902" Slides (Box 29, Folder 1 - 2)
  - "PEX 8220" Slides (Box 28, Folder 19 - 20)
  - "PEX Selects 8222" Slides (Box 28, Folder 17 - 18)
  - "PEX 8223" Slides (Box 28, Folder 15 - 16)
  - "Reading Room Jan. '97" Slides (Box 28, Folder 13 - 14)
  - "SRC Exterior Outs" Slides (Box 28, Folder 11 - 12)
  - "B.T.S. Atkins Hector Project Extra May '92" Slides (Box 28, Folder 7 - 8)
  - "B.T.S. Atkins Hector Project Repro Set May '92" Slides (Box 28, Folder 5 - 6)
  - "Projection Set Hector 1991" Slides (Box 28, Folder 3 - 4)
  - "FF Parts 5990" Slides (Box 28, Folder 1 - 2)
  - "Reading Room Jan. 97" Slides (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - "FF Parts 9095" Slides (Box 27, Folder 18 - 19)
  - "Fire Fly PCB Outs" Slides (Box 27, Folder 16 - 17)
  - "Fire Fly Show Set 5988" Slides (Box 27, Folder 14 - 15)
  - "SRC Ext. 9094" Slides (Box 27, Folder 12 - 13)
  - "Manasse August 1996" Slides (Box 27, Folder 10 - 11)
  - "3 FRED" Slides (Box 27, Folder 8 - 9)
  - "AN1 + AN2 June 1998" Slides (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - "NY Times" Slides (Box 27, Folder 5 - 6)
  - "Video Transfers" Slides (Box 27, Folder 3 - 4)
  - Building Exterior Slides (Box 27, Folder 1 - 2)
  - "Multi Flavors - 1974" Slides (Box 26, Folder 19 - 20)
  - "MSM NYT" Slides (Box 26, Folder 17 - 18)
  - "Fire Fly" Slides (Box 26, Folder 12 - 14)
  - Robert W. Taylor Retirement Party (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - SRC Equipment Photos and Negatives (Box 24, Folder 5 - 6)
  - SRC Photos - Miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - SRC Photos - Intern Picnic, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - SRC Staff Portraits (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - SRC Photos - Parties and Events (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Digital SRC Building Facade Photo (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - DEC Workshop 3-Ring Binder Contents - 1994 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - SRC - Record Inventory Transmittal (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - SRC - "Announcing Our Existence" Memo (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - "Luca 89" (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Digital SRC Consulting Agreement (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - DEC Property Removal Pass (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Compaq SRC Phone Directory (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - DEC Exit Package (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - DEC Severance and Consulting Agreements (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Digital SRC Pamphlets (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - SRC Equipment Photos - "History of SRC" (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - SRC Equipment Photos, 2 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 1 - 3)
  - SRC Equipment Photos, 1 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 1 - 4)
  - SRC - Air Conditioner Change (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - SRC - Staff Parties (Box 13, Folder 1 - 3)
  - SRC - A.V. Feasibility Study (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - SRC - Staff Photos (Box 12, Folder 1 - 3)
  - SRC - Conferences (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - SRC - Labels, 1990 - 1995 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - SRC - "SEA 2000" (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - SRC - Promotional Drafts (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Misc. SRC Papers and Publications (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Misc. SRC Memos, Notes, and Drafts (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "A Kernel Language for Modules and Abstract Data Types" (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - "Optimal Point Location in a Monotone Subdivision" (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - SRC - Retirement Party Photos (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - SRC - Misc. Memos (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Internetworking - Table of Contents (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Research Plan, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Strategy, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Workshop, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Memos, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - 'Who's Who at SRC', 1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Biographical Sketch of SRCers, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - SRC Customer Maps (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - SRC - Promotions Criteria and Job Descriptions (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Slides for a Talk, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Dear Candidate" Letter, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Resumes and CVs (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - SRC Pamphlets (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Digital News, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "Ranking Criteria for Research", etc., 1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Recruiting Contacts, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Location of SRC (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Getting Started at SRC", 1984 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "Wall Street Journal," p. 5, 1983-12-22 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Photos - SRC (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Digital Offer, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Series 5. Writing About Robert W. Taylor
  - Newspaper Articles on RWT (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Yomiuri Shimbun Article (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - "The Alcalde", July/August 2010 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - "The Alcalde", May/June 2010 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - "The Alcalde", March/April 2010 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - "The Phi Gamma Delta", Spring 2004 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - "The Phi Gamma Delta", Spring 2003 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - "The Massachusetts Historical Review", 2000 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "Scientific American", April 2000 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Paul Baran Wired Interview and Letter (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Misc. MacWeek Publications (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - DEC - "Forefront", 1996 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - The Almanac, 2000-12-11 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - News Clipping, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "Information Week", p. 59, 1985-03-18 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "The Economist", p. 87, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Digital Review", p. 15, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - News Clipping, 1984-05-14 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Digital SRC News Clippings, 1983 - 1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "LA Times", 1995-09-13 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "Mercedes Enterprise", p. 8, 1991-04-10 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Peninsula", 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Fumbling the Future" draft, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - History Notes from IEEE Spectrum, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - "Computers & Electronics", 1984 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - "High Tech Brain Drain", 1984-08-13 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - "Businessweek", p. 114B, 1983-05-09 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Businessweek", p. 138, 1983-03-28 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 'Newseek' - p. 56, 1994-08-08 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Series 6. Writing By or Featuring Robert W.Taylor
  - "Science and Technology" Oversize Illustrations (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Cartoon Originals (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Science & Technology", 1968 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Computer Science - Quo Vadis?" (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Forum '79 Talk" (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Publications and Reprints of "On the Relation of Interactive Computing..." (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "What is Computer Science?" (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "Computer Science in a Decade", 1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Technical Overview, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Plans for Experimental, Interactive Computer Network (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Time Magazine Letters to the Editor, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Reprints (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Reference Material (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Series 7. Awards and Recognition
  - Draper Prize Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - UT-Austin Correspondence and Publicity (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Draper Prize Notification (Box 18, Folder 16)